### **Curriculum Vitae Hubert Iwaniuk**

Fjord 18 8224 DA Lelystad neotyk@kungfoo.pl

page 1 of 2

### Summary

I am and have been developer, designer. Enjoy contributing back to Open Source projects. My experience lies in projects with highly scalable server systems, system integrations, performance firefighting, infrastructure development. I have further interests in automating processes that don't have to be done manually. I enjoy agile processes where business and development get closer.

## Experience

#### Sourcesense NL BV

November 2009 – present

As Senior Software Engineer in Sourcesense I advice clients on architectures and design as well as help troubleshooting high priority problems.

## **OSS Project Grizzly**

January 2009 – present

Project Grizzly <a href="https://grizzly.dev.java.net">https://grizzly.dev.java.net</a> is a scalable lightweight general purpose server framework on Java. I take care of Servlet container, HTTP stack, build based on Maven2.

Created OSGi Http Service implementation based on available Grizzly components.

Lead effort of creating HTTP Client and Grizzly HTTP Proxy.

# **OSS Maven Overview Plugin**

January 2008 – present

Maven Overview Plugin <a href="http://code.google.com/p/maven-overview-plugin/">http://code.google.com/p/maven-overview-plugin/</a> reporting plugin that graphs diagram of all dependencies (dependency graph). It supports in/exclusions. I'm maintainer of this project.

#### TomTom International BV

July 2007 – October 2009

I work as Senior Software Developer at TomTom. Migrations of TomTom's main content delivery system (TomTom Home server) from a PHP to a Java implementation. I worked on extracting valid domain models from existing unstructured data set, and performed the corresponding complex datamigrations.

Worked on homegrown subscription management system, migration from old one, and safe deployment of the new system while all customers had no interruption of services.

To get this safe transition I've led development of a shadowing proxy, that had very strong performance and stability requirements.

Created framework for configurable releases based on ideas from Maven Release Plugin.

I played senior role in teams that I worked with, that involved guidance and advice to junior team members.

### **Curriculum Vitae Hubert Iwaniuk**

Fjord 18 8224 DA Lelystad neotyk@kungfoo.pl

page 2 of 2

I've also maintained SVN repository, Nexus and Hudson.

### **NewBay Software Ltd**

August 2006 - May 2007

As Senior developer I've stabilized 6 million user base installation of Foneblog (flag product). Participated in redesigning of same product to scale to 50 million users.

Recreated email homegrown email gateway to take advantage of multi threading (about 100x more efficient than predecessor).

Create integration of Foneblog and Account and Billing System for LifeCache O2 UK.

# **KungFoo**

June 2005 – June 2006

Created architecture and design of server system for GPS fleet monitoring solution.

#### P.B. Polsoft

October 2003 - June 2005

At client I've designed and lead implementation of integration of OSS TroubleTicketing solution with Staffware (now Tibco).

Developed integration with BEA Tuxido.

#### **Education**

2004: "Staffware Training Course" - Staffware Server Objects by Staffware UK Training Services

2004: M. Sc. At Adam Mickiewicz University in Poznań

The study was completed with the thesis "Distributed information searching in TCP/IP networks utilizing CORBA Component Model".

# **Specialties**

Agile development (scrum, xp), system integration, object oriented analysis and design, scalable server architectures, Maven development.